<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music Channel on Nothing in Particular</title>
    <link>https://0xnf.github.io/categories/music-channel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music Channel on Nothing in Particular</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 13:44:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://0xnf.github.io/categories/music-channel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Channel Part 3 - Branding</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 13:44:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel2/</guid>
      <description>This is the third post in a series of posts about analyzing YouTube music channels
 Part 1 - Music Channel Introduction and Data Collection Part 2 - Analysis of Channel Activity Part 3 - Branding  Branding As a review, we&amp;rsquo;re basing our channel the behavioral patterns of some other channels:
 TheSoundYouNeed MajesticCasual MrSuicideSheep Chill Nation Eton Messy MonsterCat MikuMusicNetwork  Among their other patterns, we&amp;rsquo;re going use them as a base for how to brand our channel as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Channel Part 2 - Stats</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:50:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel1/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in a series of posts about analyzing YouTube music channels
 Part 1 - Music Channel Introduction and Data Collection Part 2 - Analysis of Channel Activity Part 3 - Branding  Your Questions, Answered We left off last time with a freshly created database full of information we could query. We sought to answer a few questions. As a reminder, those questions were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Channel Part 1 - Data</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:17:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/music/channel0/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series of posts about analyzing YouTube music channels
 Part 1 - Music Channel Introduction and Data Collection Part 2 - Analysis of Channel Activity
 Part 3 - Branding
  Background I often listen to new music on YouTube because their discovery systems unearth some occasionally great finds. After a while of listening there however you begin to realize that there are only a handful of channels that get recommended to you, and they all seem to just upload songs and let the views roll in, not unlike a radio DJ.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>