<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0xNF&#39;s Blog - This site will never be updated</title>
    <link>https://0xNF.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 0xNF&#39;s Blog - This site will never be updated</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>0xNF</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 12:10:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://0xNF.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MOOC Platforms</title>
      <link>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 12:10:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-03/</guid>
      <description>This is the third and final document in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The first post can be found here, and the previous post can be found here. This report has been adapted from a word document. 
MOOC Platforms Shim Vijay and Evin Yesudas
Table of Contents  MOOC Platforms: Analysis Report  Preface Introduction Objective of this Study  Overview  EdX Coursera Udacity NovoEd  Methodology MOOC Platform Comparison Chart Key Findings  How Are Qualitative Courses Managed Types of Certificates &amp;amp; Their Importance Free Certificate Verified Certificate Helping The Participants To Complete   MOOC Platforms: Analysis Report Preface This study focuses on the review of four leading MOOC platforms namely Coursera, EdX, NovoEd and Udacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing CCIS to the Top</title>
      <link>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 11:35:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-02/</guid>
      <description>This is the third in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The first post can be found here, the previous post can be found here, and the next post can be found here.
This report has been adapted from a word document. 
Bringing CCIS to the Top Table of Contents  Executive Summary The Introductory Course The Over Focus on Mathematics Math Overview and Applications Course Outline  Concepts, Identification, and Applications of Mathematics  The Bad Courses  Theory of Computation Programming Languages  The Hunt for Great Professors  The Qualities of a Good Professor Qualitizer Results The Hunt Continues People in Specific   Executive Summary The computer science school is facing a huge amount of competition from online courses, self-taught people, and coding bootcamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Northeastern University</title>
      <link>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 11:05:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-01/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The first post can be found here and the next post can be found here.
This report has been adapted from a word document. 
The State of Northeastern University Table of Contents  Executive Summary In Detail  Northeastern&amp;rsquo;s Desire to Compete Outside It&amp;rsquo;s Expertise MIT Building 20 Like Activist Investors, Except for University Northeastern&amp;rsquo;s Neglect of Trends in Technology and Education Imagining What Could Be What MOOCs Are Doing Right What MOOCs Are Doing Wrong The Innovators A Few Radical Ideas Post Graduate Services Joint Professorship and Co-Op Appointments at the ISEB Alternative Curriculum  The Co-Op Curriculum The Project Research Curriculum  Closing Thoughts   Executive Summary Northeastern is making an admirable expansion into research, but in doing so, it is neglecting its history as a trade school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEU Report</title>
      <link>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 10:51:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/neu-00/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The next post can be found here.
This report has been adapted from a word document. 
The NEU Report Executive Summary Nick Flower | Articulate Insights | articulateinsights.com Northeastern University, an institution that has separated itself from the pack and made its reputation by distilling trade knowledge and giving its students a leg up in industry has recently seen its focus shift to becoming more like the mainstream colleges it sought to differentiate itself from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyricall Architecture</title>
      <link>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/lyricall-architecture-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 13:21:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xNF.github.io/posts/lyricall-architecture-00/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Architecture of lyricall.net  Technology tl;dr: App Overview Front End  TypeScript Why TypeScript Redux React Why React  Back End Database - PostgreSQL  Why Postgres Database Schema Lyricall Tables Straggler Tables ASP.NET / Entity Framework Tables  Server - .NET Core 2.0 / ASP.NET Core 2.0  Why .NET Core Intermission - the DotNetStandardSpotifyWebApi library Intermission - the ASP.NET Security Project API Server Architecture Entity Framework vs Hand Crafted SQL Automatic Timed Services Services Models Validation Scanning  Hosting Digital Ocean  Security Backups CI/CD  Microsoft Azure  Backups CI/CD  Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt   Architecture of lyricall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>