<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articulate Insights on Nothing in Particular</title>
    <link>https://0xnf.github.io/tags/articulate-insights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articulate Insights on Nothing in Particular</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 15:34:47 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0xnf.github.io/tags/articulate-insights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The NEU Report - Survey of MOOC Platforms</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 15:34:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/04/</guid>
      
        <description>This is the third and final document in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The first post can be found here, and the previous post can be found here. This report has been adapted from a word document.
MOOC Platforms Shim Vijay and Evin Yesudas
Table of Contents  MOOC Platforms: Analysis Report  Preface Introduction Objective of this Study   Overview  EdX Coursera Udacity NovoEd   Methodology MOOC Platform Comparison Chart Key Findings  How Are Qualitative Courses Managed Types of Certificates &amp;amp; Their Importance Free Certificate Verified Certificate Helping The Participants To Complete    MOOC Platforms: Analysis Report Preface This study focuses on the review of four leading MOOC platforms namely Coursera, EdX, NovoEd and Udacity.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEU Report - Bringing CCIS To The Top</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 15:34:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/03/</guid>
      
        <description>This is the third in a multiple part document originally written in 2015. The first post can be found here, the previous post can be found here, and the next post can be found here. This report has been adapted from a word document.
Bringing CCIS to the Top Table of Contents  Executive Summary The Introductory Course The Over Focus on Mathematics Math Overview and Applications Course Outline  Concepts, Identification, and Applications of Mathematics   The Bad Courses  Theory of Computation Programming Languages   The Hunt for Great Professors  The Qualities of a Good Professor Qualitizer Results The Hunt Continues People in Specific    Executive Summary The computer science school is facing a huge amount of competition from online courses, self-taught people, and coding bootcamps.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEU Report - The State of Northeastern University</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 15:34:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/02/</guid>
      
        <description>Northeastern is making an admirable expansion into research, but in doing so, it is neglecting its history as a trade school. These two things can coexist, but the current implementation is a deal with the devil, and the tradeoff is likely to come back to bite the university in the coming years as technical revolutions and social forces make a university education an increasingly hard sell.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NEU Report - Executive Summary</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 15:34:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/neu/01/</guid>
      
        <description>Northeastern University, an institution that has separated itself from the pack and made its reputation by distilling trade knowledge and giving its students a leg up in industry has recently seen its focus shift to becoming more like the mainstream colleges it sought to differentiate itself from. Although the co-op program is fantastic, its existence is dangerous in that it obscures the truth. Just because the university has such a program doesn’t mean it isn’t losing its edge.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>