<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data cleanup on Nothing in Particular</title>
    <link>https://0xnf.github.io/tags/data-cleanup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data cleanup on Nothing in Particular</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 07:22:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0xnf.github.io/tags/data-cleanup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Levine Mk. II</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/mk2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 07:22:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/mk2/</guid>
      <description>Machine Levine Mk. II is the second of the Matt Bots, and the first of which can produce any kind of coherent output. A brief description of his capabilities are described at his homepage over at http://machinelevine.winetech.com/bots/ml2, but we&amp;rsquo;ll deal with some deeper ideas behind his creation and operation here.
Data Collection Mk. II uses the same initial corpus that Mk. I uses. For more details on data collection, refer to Mk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Levine Mk. I</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/mk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/mk1/</guid>
      <description>This is a description of how the first of the Matt Bots came into existence. Few things in this document should be interpreted as the best or even a correct way to do anything - this bot is an academic exercise. That being said, here is how he was made.
Data Collection Like the general post describes, the data used to train the Matt model was derived from Matt Levine&amp;rsquo;s at-the-time 571-count archive of Money Stuff articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Levine</title>
      <link>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/machinelevine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 19:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xnf.github.io/posts/ml/machinelevine/</guid>
      <description>The Goal In order to better understand machine learning, I decided to see if I could get a neural network to write articles like Matt Levine. The original goal was to sort Spotify songs by male or female vocals, but I had been learning all of this stuff by following along with the fast.ai courses, and that specific use case was a bit afield of the coursework and forum discussions happening in the MOOC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
